q1
Merging with smaller auxiliary array. Suppose that the subarray \mathtt{a[0]}a[0] to \mathtt{a[n-1]}a[n−1] is sorted and the subarray \mathtt{a[n]}a[n] to \mathtt{a[2*n-1]}a[2∗n−1] is sorted. How can you merge the two subarrays so that \mathtt{a[0]}a[0] to \mathtt{a[2*n-1]}a[2∗n−1] is sorted using an auxiliary array of length nn (instead of 2n2n)?
Copy left half of the array into aux. 
Merge based on aux and right part of the array


Q2
Counting inversions. An inversion in an array a[\,]a[] is a pair of entries a[i]a[i] and a[j]a[j] such that i < ji<j but a[i] > a[j]a[i]>a[j]. Given an array, design a linearithmic algorithm to count the number of inversions.

use same divide and conquer algorithm as merge sort, the total num of conversion is the sum of  the following :

a. inversions in the first half , that is i < j < n/2
b. inversions in the second half , that is n/2 <= i < j
c. inversions cross the first half and second half , that is i < n/2 <= j


Q3
Shuffling a linked list. Given a singly-linked list containing nn items, rearrange the items uniformly at random. Your algorithm should consume a logarithmic (or constant) amount of extra memory and run in time proportional to n \log nnlogn in the worst case.

Perform the same procedure as merge sort. When merging, instead of selecting an element (one-by-one) from the two lists in sorted order, flip a coin. Choose whether to pick an element from the first or from the second list based on the result of the coin flip.