Q1
Nuts and bolts. A disorganized carpenter has a mixed pile of nn nuts and nn bolts. The goal is to find the corresponding pairs of nuts and bolts. Each nut fits exactly one bolt and each bolt fits exactly one nut. By fitting a nut and a bolt together, the carpenter can see which one is bigger (but the carpenter cannot compare two nuts or two bolts directly). Design an algorithm for the problem that uses n \log nnlogn compares (probabilistically).

First performs a partition by picking last element of bolts array as pivot, rearrange the array of nuts and returns the partition index ‘i’ such that all nuts smaller than nuts[i] are on the left side and all nuts greater than nuts[i] are on the right side. 
Next using the nuts[i] as pivot we can partition the array of bolts. Partitioning operations can easily be implemented in O(n). This operation also makes nuts and bolts array nicely partitioned. 
Now we apply this partitioning recursively on the left and right sub-array of nuts and bolts.


Q2
Selection in two sorted arrays. Given two sorted arrays a[\; ]a[] and b[ \; ]b[], of sizes n_1n 
1
​	  and n_2n 
2
​	 , respectively, design an algorithm to find the k^{th}k 
th
  largest key. The order of growth of the worst case running time of your algorithm should be \log nlogn, where n = n_1 + n_2n=n 
1
​	 +n 
2
​	 .

Version 1: n_1 = n_2n 
1
​	 =n 
2
​	  and k = n/2k=n/2
Version 2: k = n/2k=n/2
Version 3: no restrictions

Array A and B 
New array A[0]::B::A[:]
left pt = B[1] elem and move left pt until B[left]>=pt, curr left is the pos for A[0] and partition
recursive do the same thing for relevant partitioned part
O(logn)


Q3
Decimal dominants. Given an array with nn keys, design an algorithm to find all values that occur more than n/10n/10 times. The expected running time of your algorithm should be linear.

First pass: Counter array  count occurrence
Second pass : res the large size array

Recursive determine the (n/10)th largest key using quickselect and check if it occurs more than n/10 times

Maybe wrong
这9个辅助空间aux怎么使用呢？可采用俄罗斯方块的消去一行的思路。只不过这里消去一行的情况是该行中元素各不相同。

1. 遍历数组array中的每个元素array[i]

2. 如果array[i]在aux中存在，将其在aux中的计数+1

3. 如果array[i]在aux中不存在

　　3.1 如果aux未满，将其放入aux中，并记录其个数为1

　　3.2 如果aux已满，将aux中已经存在的各个元素的计数都减去1，直到某个元素的个数变成0，将array[i]放入aux中该位置处，并记录其个数为1

4. 出现次数超过n/10的元素在array遍历完了之后，还会继续存在于aux中，当然aux中可存在着位于array后方但出现次数不满足要求的元素。这时只需要遍历aux的同时再遍历一遍array，记录aux中各个元素在array中出现的次数，将其中出现次数真正超过n/10的元素找出来即可。