Q1
Dynamic median. Design a data type that supports insert in logarithmic time, find-the-median in constant time, and remove-the-median in logarithmic time.

One min-heap and one max-heap.
Every time you insert, compare the new element with those at the top of the heaps in order to decide where to insert it. If the new element is greater than the current median, it goes to the min-heap. If it is less than the current median, it goes to the max heap. Then you might need to rebalance. If the sizes of the heaps differ by more than one element, extract the min/max from the heap with more elements and insert it into the other heap.


Q2
Randomized priority queue. Describe how to add the methods \mathtt{sample()}sample() and \mathtt{delRandom()}delRandom() to our binary heap implementation. The two methods return a key that is chosen uniformly at random among the remaining keys, with the latter method also removing that key. The \mathtt{sample()}sample() method should take constant time; the \mathtt{delRandom()}delRandom() method should take logarithmic time. Do not worry about resizing the underlying array.

Random sample number from 1 to N, return item in that index (remember the fact that an array implementation is used)
delSample swap the random() element with the last element and move counter pointer -1

Q3
Taxicab numbers. A taxicab number is an integer that can be expressed as the sum of two cubes of positive integers in two different ways: a^3 + b^3 = c^3 + d^3a 
3
 +b 
3
 =c 
3
 +d 
3
 . For example, 17291729 is the smallest taxicab number: 9^3 + 10^3 = 1^3 + 12^39 
3
 +10 
3
 =1 
3
 +12 
3
 . Design an algorithm to find all taxicab numbers less than nn.

Version 1: Use time proportional to n^2 \log nn 
2
 logn and space proportional to n^2n 
2
 .
Version 2: Use time proportional to n^2 \log nn 
2
 logn and space proportional to nn.

Observe that every line and every row is sorted in ascending order. Let PQ be the priority queue. First we put the biggest element in the priority queue. Then perform the following, as long as the PQ is not empty:

There exists an O(N) space solution based on a priority queue. Time complexity is O(N^2 logN). To sketch out the idea of the algorithm, here is the matrix M such that M[i][j] = i^3 + j^3 (of course, the matrix is never created in memory)

Pop the biggest element from PQ
add adajcent element above if the PQ doesn't have any element from that row
add adajcent element on the left if the PQ doesn't have any element from that column, and if it is not under the diagonal of the matrix (to avoid redundant elements)